we are
living with technologies that are
intentionally
designed to make us fearful
to make us panic to put us back into our
brain stem
to avoid our higher human thinking
and our even our mammalian thinking
we have a system right now with social
media that broadly
narrows the space of human sense making
and choice
by reinforcing the old biases yes those
other people on the other side are still
wrong
yes uh you know those people over there
still don't like me or so i still need
that attention from them
we're narrowing the human experience and
i the big question we're going to have
is
can we go back and treat this as
something sacred china's fault it should
have never happened not here to call out
his lies everybody knows he's a liar
[Music]
why should i be different than the two
of you
if you live in a in a
digital haunted house that's designed by
stamford behavioral engineers
to make you hate to make you fear
what do you think's gonna happen you
know it's just
espec and then you grow up in it as a
child
what i like and what i share and what i
comment on what my mouse hovers over the
analytics of all of that or such
that after i've done about 300 likes
facebook can predict what i will like
better than my spouse
and after i've gone further it actually
has a psychographic profile on me that
is asymmetric to anything that any human
cia agent or whatever could have ever
had previously so
what it curates for is a combination of
bias
and limbic hijack which is outrage
group identity and certainty i might
have someone
who is in oakland who they look on their
facebook feed and they just see
cops killing black people like their
whole facebook feed because that
actually maximizes their time on site
and they're sharing an engagement that
maximizes other people's time on site
and i might have somebody
in texas trump supporting and all they
see is
people wrongly attacking cops and black
on black violence
and black on white violence and both of
these people are getting vicariously
traumatized
by what they're seeing to the point that
they're having trauma reactions and they
feel like it's a war zone and they have
to pick up arms and go out into the
street
what are the tools that we can start
taking back control
ourselves of what's going on the problem
is is when technology knows us better
than we know ourselves
and if you don't know yourself as well
as the technology does
um you're going to lose we need to
build our tools from a deeper place
a place of wisdom our tech process is so
out of alignment with
deeper wisdom life's natural flow
that has to shift make sure that in your
conversations you return to a positive
view
and reflect on all the goodness that's
happening right now
what are all the things that you're
seeing people do for one another
what are the ways in which people have
extended care to you
or concern or kindness and just be sure
that we don't let the negativity bias of
our evolution
take over our perception you look in
somebody else's eyes for five seconds
breathe together you know the great
conspiracy just breathe together with
someone else
and all of these painstakingly evolved
mechanisms for social coherence
get reactivated
[Music]
you